美国家庭影院 出品
联合制作: 梦工厂 与 PLAYTON公司
领衔主演:埃奥恩・贝利 迈克尔・库德利兹 戴尔・戴伊
里克・格梅兹 斯科特・格里米斯 达米安・路易斯
朗・利文斯通 詹姆斯・马迪奥 尼尔・麦克多诺
雷升・L・莫雷诺 大卫・休默 马泰・塞特尔
与 :唐尼・沃尔伯格
角色的分派: 利伯曼/巴顿
视觉效果总监:安格斯・ 比克尔顿
特殊效果监督员: 乔斯・威廉姆斯
服装设计师: 安娜・谢帕德
编辑:诺里・奥蒂
音乐: 迈克尔・凯曼
制作设计 : 安东尼・布拉特
摄影指导:乔尔・ J・ 兰塞姆
监督指导: 艾力克・简得森
制作人: 玛丽・理查兹
监督制片人: 埃里克・ 柏克
联合执行制片人: 史蒂芬・安布洛斯 加里・高依兹曼 托尼・ 托
执行制片人: 汤姆・ 汉克斯 斯蒂文・ 斯皮尔伯格
兄弟连作者: 史蒂芬・安布洛斯
编剧:埃里克・延德里森 埃里克・博克
导演:迈克尔・所罗门
兄 弟 连
第十集
得 分
( 1945年7月 )
(奥地利 札兰西 )
我和路易士・尼克森决定加入伞兵部队
It was more than three years since Lewis Nixon and I...
至今已经三年多
...decided to join the paratroops.
距离我们首次参战也一年多了
And more than a year since we'd first gone to war...
当时不知道我们会发生什么事
...not knowing what would happen to us.
要打多久 在哪里结束
How long we'd be fighting where we'd end up.
我当然没料到自己会出现在这样的地方
I certainly didn't expect to find myself in a place like this.
我猜是你
I thought it might be you.
早安
'Morning.
我听到报导说有个红发的爱斯基摩人在此出没
I heard reports about a red-headed Eskimo.
我就想过来看个究竟
Thought I'd check it out.
你要跟我一起晨泳吗?
Come to join me for a morning swim?
是哦 你太了解我了
Yeah. You know me so well.
拿去 这是泽林斯基给你的
Here, it's from Zielinski.
太好了
Oh, great.
那是什么?
What is that?
我遇到了团部的摄影师
Ran into the regimental photographer.
他说他有506团的照片
Said he had all these photographs of the 506th...
从塔可亚基地到现在
...going all the way back to Toccoa.
我用好几把鲁格枪换来的
I traded them for a couple of Lugers.
那可真划算
That's a bargain.
这里结束后你想做什么?
What do you think you'll do after this?
弄个早餐吃
Get some breakfast.
不是 再之后呢?
No, after, after.
真有趣 你也提到这
Well, it's funny you should mention it...
因为我跟辛克上校开过会
...'cause I had a meeting with Colonel Sink.
真的?
Really?
对
Yeah.
讨论到留下来的可能性
Yeah, he and I discussed the possibility of staying.
留在陆军?
In the Army?
对
Yeah.
当做事业
Yeah, as a career.
你怎么说?
What'd you say?
我说我会考虑
I said I'd think about it.
你觉得纽泽西州如何?
What do you think about New Jersey?
纽泽西?
New Jersey?
在纽泽西的尼克森有间公司
There's a company in Nixon, New Jersey.
叫做尼克森化肥产品
It's called "Nixon Nitration Works".
听来挺动人的
Sounds picturesque.
我刚好认识老板
Yeah, well, oddly enough I know the owners.
他可能希望我接手事业
Probably gonna expect me to make something of myself.
我想也许我该拉你进来
I thought maybe I'd drag you with me.
你是在提供我工作机会吗?
Are you offering me a job?
得看你在面试时的表现
We'll see how you do in your interview...
可是有像你这样的历炼
...but, you know, a man of your qualifications...
我想我可以尽量找个和你现在薪水差不多的职位
...I think we can probably scrape something up. Commensurate with your current salary level.
好 我会考虑看看
Yeah, I'll think about it.
我真的很感激
I really appreciate it.
你考虑看看
Yeah, just think about it.
好的
Yeah.
工作机会 难以想象
Job offers. Hard to fathom.
战争都还没有结束
And the war wasn't even over.
我还在慢慢适应有热水澡跟晨泳的日子
I was still getting used to hot showers and morning swims.
我们在五月初进入巴伐利亚
We'd entered Bavaria in early May...
希望能够攻下贝希特斯加登
...with the hopes of capturing Berchtesgaden.
这个著名的城镇高居于阿尔卑斯山区
This famous town, high in the Alps...
是纳粹党的精神大本营
...was the Nazi party's symbolic home...
而且第三帝国的首领们在此都有住所
...and all the heads of the Third Reich had houses there.
虽然希特勒已死 他却命令武装党卫军将此处
Although Hitler was dead, he had apparently ordered the SS to make it their last stand...
当成对抗盟军进攻的最后守卫据点
...from which to mount a guerrilla resistance against the Allied advance.
第一步就是封锁道路
The first step was blocking the roads.
工兵应该何时出现?
When are we expecting the engineers to arrive?
半个小时前
Half an hour ago.
他们来之前我们只能困在这里
We're stuck here until they do, Nix.
如果你是党卫军...
Well, if you're the SS...
也不会让我们跳着华尔兹进入希特勒的房子
...you're not gonna let us waltz into Hitler's house.
你也会朝我们丢石头
Probably throw a few rocks at us yourself.
如果你要找人绕道攻上山头
If you want someone to find a way up that mountain...
Ｅ连已准备好也很愿意去
...Easy Company is ready.
我了解
Duly noted.
我也向辛克上校这样建议了
I already recommended you to Colonel Sink.
咱们去找出希特勒的巢穴吧
Let's go find out where Hitler lived.
朗 我们不确定上面有什么
Ron, we're not sure what's up there.
上校不希望我们冒不必要的险
The Colonel doesn't want us taking any unnecessary risks.
那就让法国人先一步攻下鹰巢?
So, the French are gonna beat us to the Eagle's Nest.
各位 我刚和勒克莱尔将军通话
Gents, I just had a conversation with General Leclerc.
他说他是第一位进入巴黎的将领
He said he was first into Paris...
也想第一个进入贝希特斯加登
...and by God he wanted to be first into Berchtesgaden.
我说我明白他的意恩
Told him I understood his point.
你现在动员第二营抢在法国混蛋的前面
You fire up 2nd battalion and outflank that French son of a bitch.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
我要Ｅ连做先头部队
I want Easy Company in the lead.
叫弟兄们在下面高速公路上集合
Have the men assemble on the highway.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
诡异 没看到半个居民
Eerie. Not even any natives.
因为没人能否认这是个纯纳粹的城镇
That's 'cause this is the one town you can't deny being a true Nazi.
你是什么意思?
What do you mean?
住在这里你就知道了
Well, you have to be to live here.
我们得帮上校找个落脚的地方
Need to find some place we can put the Colonel.
那里如何?
How about right there?
( 贝希特斯加登旅馆 )
别拿走
No, no.
凯蒂一定会爱死这个
Kitty would love this.
有多少新娘能够拿到希特勒送的结婚贺札?
How many brides get a wedding present from Hitler?
你要不要拿一半走?
You wanna take half?
我没办法全部带走
I can't carry all this.
你知道不管谁在我们之后进来
You know, whoever comes in here after us...
都会把所有没钉死的全搬走
...is gonna take whatever isn't nailed down.
嗯
Well...
可不希望他们有这机会
...wouldn't want that to happen.
好东西
Nice.
你想都别想
Don't even think about it.
温特斯少校 长官!
Major Winters. Sir.
摩尔
More.
请求登山许可 长官
Permission to climb the mountain, sir?
进攻鹰巢
Eagle's Nest?
这是什么?
What is this?
等一下
Wait one minute.
哈利 叫Ｆ连加强守护旅馆 在城西设置路障
Harry, have F Company put a double guard on the hotel. Set up roadblocks on the west side of town.
我要在此设置营总部 将北边封锁准备接收战俘
I want battalion HQ, seal off the north side and prepare for prisoners.
葛兰特中士
Sergeant Grant.
还有 哈利 不要有人受伤 现在不能
And, Harry, nobody gets hurt, not now.
那Ｅ连呢?
And Easy?
Ｅ连由奥柏萨尔斯堡上山
Easy will head up the mountain through the Obersalzburg...
攻下鹰巢
...and take the Eagle's Nest.
冲啊 骏马!
Hi-ho, Silver!
老鹰之巢是用纳粹的钱帮希特勒盖的...
The Eagle's Nest was a surprise birthday present for Hitler...
一个惊喜生日札物
...built with Nazi party money.
是一座标高八千英尺的石材碉堡
A mountaintop stone retreat 8,000 feet up...
由一座镀金的电梯进出
...accessible by a gold-plated elevator.
这是他帝国皇冠上的一颗宝石
It was one of the crown jewels of his empire...
可是他却有畏高症
...and the man was afraid of heights.
这是敬他的
Here's to him.
不是 可恶 听着
No, goddamn it, listen.
希特勒 不 不...
Hitler, Hitler, no.
- 希姆莱、戈培尔... - 有没有人说你不会讲笑话
Hitler, Himmler, Goering, Goebbels.
教宗走进一间酒吧
and the pope walk into a bar...
- 因为他喝了太多... - 事情就是这么发生的
- Because he drinks too much... - That's how it starts.
阿道夫! 我喜欢你的鹰巢
Hey, Adolf. Love your Eagle's Nest.
我希望你不介意 我们已经把它当做自己家
I hope you don't mind. We made ourselves at home.
我喜欢你这里的布置
Love what you've done with it.
来一杯吧 快点
Hey, hey, have a drink. Come on.
我们才能说终于看到你喝酒了
Just so as we can say we saw you do it.
注意听好
Listen up.
刚从军团来的命令
From Corps, just came in.
即刻生效
Effective immediately.
所有的部队暂时在原地驻守
All troops stand fast on present positions.
原地驻守?
Standing fast.
你们要听吗?
Wanna hear it?
准备好了吗 听好 德军投降了!
Ready for it, listen up. The German army surrendered.
我有个礼物给你 来吧!
I got a present for you, come on.
- 就这样吗? - 没错
- Is it? - yeah.
- 这是什么地方? - 赫曼戈林的房子
- What is this place? - Hermann Goering's house.
昨天发现后便派双哨看守
We discovered it yesterday. Had it on double guard ever since.
这个我可以见证 长官
I can vouch for that.
等不及要下哨了吗 欧基夫?
Oh, anxious to get off duty, O'Keefe?
没有 只是有太多要看要做的事 长官
No, there's just so much to see and do, sir.
上万瓶世界上最好的烈酒
Ten thousand bottles of the world's finest liquor...
葡萄酒及香槟为Ｅ连记下了欧战结束的那一天
...wine, and champagne helped Easy Company mark the day the war in Europe came to an end.
全都是你的了
It's all yours.
想拿多少就拿多少 然后叫每连载一卡车走
Take what you want and have each company take a truckload.
我们明早就要前住奥地利 不用留给后面的人
We're going to Austria in the morning. Don't feel obliged to leave stuff for whoever comes next.
奥地利吗 长官
Austria, sir?
"ＶＥ"日快乐
Happy V.E. Day.
对
Yeah.
"ＶＥ"日?
V.E. day?
欧战胜利日
Victory in Europe.
欧战胜利日快乐
Happy V.E. Day.
不像一支攻击性的战斗部队
Instead of an aggressive combat unit...
我们反倒成了占领军
...we became an occupation force...
没有人想离开贝希特加登
...and no one wanted to leave Berchtesgaden...
直到我们看到了奥地利
...until they saw Austria.
你想上级会要我们爬上山还是滑雪下来?
So, you reckon they'll make us run up those or ski down them?
你好
Hey, how are you?
需要帮忙吗?
Need a hand there?
他爱你
He loves you!
小姐 你好吗?
Hey, lady, how are you?
战争结束了
I think the war is over.
我们在这儿会很舒服的
We'll be comfortable here.
我在想当战争终于结束时
I wonder what will happen to us...
像你我这样的人 命运将会是如何?
...to people like you and me when there are finally no more wars to occupy us.
叫你的部队缴械
Have all your men collect the weapons...
然后把它放在教堂 学校跟机场
...deposit them at the church, at the school, and at the airfield.
很好
Very well.
请你收下这个当做是我正式的投降 少校
Please accept this as my formal surrender, Major.
这样会比放在一个文书兵的桌上来的好
It is better than to lay it on the desk of a clerk.
你可以留着你的手枪 上校
You may keep your sidearm, Colonel.
陆军及海军陆战队弟兄的英勇牺牲 为正在进行中的
Heroic dead of a combined army and marine force mark the grim battlefield of Okinawa...
战史上最血腥战斗之一的冲绳岛之役留下注脚
...where one of the worst battles of the war is being fought.
有上千名美国人受伤 并且已经有数千名
Thousands of Yanks have been wounded or sacrificed their lives...
为了设法将疯狂的敌人赶出他们的巢穴而阵亡
...to drive a fanatical foe from this base.
延着日军南边的防线
Along the Jap's southern defense line...
美军遭遇到空前猛烈的炮击而进度缓慢
...the Yanks progress slowly facing one of the fiercest artillery barrages of the war.
每一小步进展都是藉由英勇对抗
Each small advance is gained by sheer grit...
强做困兽之斗的敌军自杀攻击
...in the face of withering fire from a suicidal enemy...
并将其慢慢逐回山头而取得
...being slowly hammered back into the hills.
战事惨烈的进行着 而我们的伤亡惨重
The going is brutal and our casualties are high...
可是冲绳是战胜日本的一大步
...but Okinawa is the next big step towards victory over Japan.
这个胜利唯有藉着努力工作
A victory that can only be won by work...
战争债券以及英勇的牺性
...war bonds, and heroic sacrifice.
- 我们什么时候要去? - 还没有确定日期
- So, when are we going? - We don't have a date yet.
要现在跟弟兄们说吗?
Are we to tell the men right away?
有些人反而会拿到足够点数而退伍
Some of them will have enough points to go home instead.
不会很多 如果只得过紫心勋章的话
Not many if their only medal's a Purple Heart.
我想我们几个都会有足够的点数
I think most of us here will have enough.
我们每个人将要决定下一步要做什么
And each of us will have to decide what to do.
我不知还要在此待命多久
I don't know how long we're waiting here for orders...
可是我要决定留下的老兵...
...but I want those veterans who are staying...
及所有新兵随时备战
...and all new replacements, ready to fight.
这表示要做射击训练
That means rifle ranges.
紧急受命演习与部队检讨
That means daily close order drills. That means troop reviews...
可是最重要的是体能训练
...but, above all, it means physical training.
叫你的士官们去执行
Get your NCOs on it.
他们会爱死你的
They're gonna love you.
你蹲下来干什么 派康提?
What are you crouching down for, Perco?
你以为鹿会向你开几枪吗?
Think the deer's gonna shoot back?
你少管我
Leave me alone.
你们何不都闭嘴
How about you all just shut up...
让西福弟帮我们射只晚餐来吃?
...and let Shifty kill us some dinner?
怎么了 大牛?
What's the matter, Bull?
你吃腻三餐的干马铃薯吗?
You tired of eating dried up spuds three times a day?
我想到个主意 干脆我们把大牛给杀了
Hey, you know what, I got an idea. Why don't we just shoot Bull here...
来喂连上一个星期
...and feed the company for a week?
可恶 西福弟
Oh, goddamn it, Shifty.
你让它跑了 陆军一定很庆幸你要退伍了
You let him get away. Army ought to be glad to be rid of you.
希望是这样 可是看来他们还要我多留一阵
I wish, you know. It seems they want me to stay around awhile.
- 你没开玩笑吧? - 你还需要几点?
- Are you serious? - How many points you need?
15点
Fifteen.
15点? 天啊 我还以为我已经够多点了
Fifteen! Jesus Christ, I thought I had it bad.
我没得过紫心勋章 也没受过伤
No Purple Hearts, never was injured.
全连各排注意! 立正!
Company! Platoon! Attention!
上右肩~托枪!
Right shoulder. Arm!
枪~放下!
Order. Arms!
稍息
At ease.
泰勒将军知道有很多老兵
General Taylor is aware that many veterans...
包括参与诺曼底空降的老兵
...including Normandy veterans...
还没有累积到足够退伍的85分点数
...still do not have the 85 points required to be discharged.
在今天这个D日纪念日
On this the anniversary of D-day...
他给大家一次抽奖机会
...he has authorized a lottery to send...
每连有一位兄弟能退伍返乡
...one man home in each company...
即刻生效
...effective immediately.
Ｅ连的中奖者
For Easy Company, the winner is...
拜托
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
兵籍号码13066266
Serial number 13066266.
戴若包尔斯中士
Sergeant Darrell C. Powers.
西福弟
Shifty
这是你应得的 西福弟
That's how it's done, Shifty.
恭喜了 西福弟
Congratulations, Shifty.
葛兰特中士负责带第二排去路口检查哨换防
Sergeant Grant will see to it that 2nd Platoon takes over at the crossroads checkpoint...
从今晚10点开始
...beginning tonight at 2200 hours.
- 周年庆就此结束了 - 没错
- So much for our anniversary. - No shit.
泰勒将军也同时宣布101空降师
General Taylor has also announced that the 101st Airborne Division...
绝对会被重新布置在太平洋
...will definitely be redeployed to the Pacific.
所以从明早6点开始
So, beginning tomorrow, at 0600 hours...
我们要开始作战训练
...we will begin training to go to war.
进来
Come in.
我无意来打扰你 长官
I don't mean to interrupt you, sir.
我只是想来...道别
I just wanted to say goodbye.
你知道 你是...
You know, you was...
你是...
You was...
嗯...
Well...
我跟着您好久了
It's been a long time.
东西都带齐了吗?
You got everything you need?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
我把战利品收好了 大部分是手枪
I gathered up my loot. Pistols mainly.
表格都写好了 我甚至已经拿了退伍金
Paperwork's all done. I even got my back pay in my pocket.
回到在维吉尼亚的家
Back, back home in Virginia...
嗯...
Well...
我只是不知道该如何向别人解释这一切
I just don't rightly know how I'm gonna explain all this.
你知道
You see, I've...
我曾见过...我曾见过...
I've seen... I've seen...
你是一个非常杰出的军人 西福弟
You're a hell of a fine soldier, Shifty.
没有什么需要解释的
There's nothing more to explain.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
两天后 西福弟包尔斯坐上卡车 朝回家的船出发
Two days later, Shifty Powers was on a truck headed for the rear and a boat home.
不幸被一辆由别团一个酒醉的下士驾驶的车迎面撞上
Unfortunately the truck was hit head-on by a drunken corporal from another regiment.
西福弟骨盆碎裂
Shifty had a broken pelvis...
一只手骨折 并有严重的脑震荡
...a broken arm, and a bad concussion.
虽然活了下来 可是得在医院多住几个月
He survived, but spent the next few months in a series of hospitals.
我真希望我能说 他是我们在奥地利的唯一伤亡人员
I wish I could say that he was our only casualty in Austria.
我已经决定了 尼克
I've made up my mind, Nix.
一旦我集满点数我就要回去找凯蒂
I got the points, I'm going back to Kitty.
哈利 你真的还认为 凯蒂没跟被退役的男人跑了
Harry, do you really think that Kitty hasn't run off with some 4-F by now?
王八蛋 一点都不好笑
Son of a bitch. That's not even funny.
哈利 别理他
Harry, ignore him.
我怎么告诉她说 我本来终于有机会回家找她
How am I supposed to tell her I had the chance to go home to her finally...
却为了想要空降东京而决定放弃?
...but decided not to, so I could go jump on Tokyo?
好 那就别告诉她
All right, so don't tell her.
反正她已经等了你三年了 对不对?
Besides, she's waited for you for three years, right?
我们去东京再回来差不多只要两年 最多三年
We'll be to Tokyo and back in two years, three tops.
可能在你去之前就会结束了
It'll probably be over before you even get there.
事实上 你会在奥地利待上半年准备出发
The reality is you're gonna sit here in Austria for six months waiting to go...
而我会回到我的温柔乡生小孩
...and I'm gonna be back in Wilkes-Barre making babies.
- 你还没告诉他? - 还没 我就是没办法让他闭嘴
- You didn't tell him? - No, I couldn't get him to shut up.
什么? 告诉我什么?
What, tell me what?
这位荣誉军人申请转调
Guts and Glory here applied for a transfer.
什么?
What?
第13空降师马上要向太平洋战区出发
13th Airborne are heading out for the Pacific right away.
如果我要去 我在这里需要做个了结
If I'm going, I wanna get it over with.
你也要去吗?
Are you in on this too?
我不能让他一个人去 他会找不到路的
I can't let him go by himself. He doesn't know where it is.
你要离开兄弟们?
You're leaving the men?
他们不再需要我了
They don't need me anymore.
在诺曼底受伤?
Wounded in Normandy?
是 长官 在腿部 只是轻微的皮肉伤
Yes, sir. In the leg. It was a minor flesh wound.
Ｅ连在那里损失了24名兄弟
Company E lost 24 men killed there.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
其中17名是在我连连长搭乘的飞机上 他们在D日那天坠毁了
Seventeen of those were in my company commander's plane. It went down on D-day.
所以你在D日那天受命指挥全连?
So, you were given command of the company on D-day?
是的
That's right.
退回你原来的据点
Fall back to your original positions!
其他人保持火力
Everyone else maintain your pace of fire!
在荷兰 他们...把你升去当副营长
In Holland they bumped you to battalion XO.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
混蛋们把你的连抢走了
Bastards took your company away.
我在那里开了我最后一枪
I fired my last shots there.
在整个战争里?
For the whole damn war?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
你未发一枪一弹经历了巴斯通之役?
You got through Bastogne without having to fire your weapon?
正确 长官
That is correct, sir.
而你一直都在战线上?
And you were on the line the whole time?
是 长官
Yes, sir.
无法想象对领导者有更严酷的考验
Can't imagine a tougher test for a leader...
在那些状况下撑过围城之苦
...having to sit through a siege like that under those conditions.
我们熬过来了
We got through it.
找掩体 找散兵坑
Find some cover, find a foxhole!
快点 找掩体
Come on, take cover! Take cover!
快点 快找掩体
Come on, find some cover!
你为什么要转调?
Why do you want a transfer?
对不起 长官?
Sorry, sir?
我说你为何要离开你的兄弟?
I said, why do you want to leave your men?
不是这样的 长官
It's not that, sir.
我是想太平洋还有战事
It's just that if the war was still on in the Pacific...
我还能够协助作战
...and I could do some good over there.
你是不是想当上师长?
Looking to have your own division someday?
不是的 长官
No, sir.
你不想在陆军里发展?
Not going to make a career of the army?
不是 我不知道 长官
No. Well, I don't know, sir.
如果你是想获得更多的作战经验
Because if you think you need more combat experience...
来争取你头盔上的星星的话
...to get stars on your helmet...
让我告诉你一件事 孩子
...let me tell you something, son.
你做的够多了
You've done enough.
谢谢你 长官 那不是我的目的
Thank you, sir. That's not my objective.
少校 这次会面 我增加了对你和101师的尊敬
Major, I took this meeting out of respect for your achievements and for the 101st.
如果他们最终会被派往太平洋 你应该指挥其中的一个营
If they do go to the Pacific eventually you should be running one of the battalions.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
老实说 我认为你的兄弟有权利将你留下来
And frankly, your men have earned the right to keep you around.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
所以我暂时得留在奥地利待命
So, I would stay in Austria for the time being waiting for orders...
想办法看好无敌可战的士兵们
...and trying to watch over soldiers who had no enemy to fight.
李 我不喜欢这样
Lieb, I fucking hate this.
拜托 他们已经指认他了
Oh, Jesus Christ, they fingered him.
他曾出现在营房里 韦伯
He was in the fucking room, Web.
在集中营的一个波兰人说那家伙就住在这里
A Polack who was at the slave camps said this is where he lives, here.
- 哪个集中营? - 管他是哪个
- Which camp? - Whatever camp.
我是直接受命的 而且我乐于奉命行事
I'm under direct orders and I'm happy to follow it.
这是你的私事吗 乔?
Is this a personal thing, Joe?
什么?
What?
这是你的私事吗?
Is this personal to you?
不是 这是个命令
No, it's a goddamn order.
温特斯少校知道这件事吗?
Does Major Winters know about this?
这无关紧要了
Doesn't matter here.
无关紧要个屁!
Oh, the fuck it doesn't.
如果这家伙只是个普通的士兵呢?
What if this guy's just a soldier?
如果他是个跟党卫军毫无瓜葛的军官呢?
What if he's an officer with no ties to the SS?
如果他根本是无辜的?
If he's innocent? You know...
如果他是奴隶营里的指挥官?
...what if he's a fucking Nazi commandant of a slave camp?
哪一个? 哪个集中营? 你没有任何证据
Which one, which camp? You don't have any proof.
你有去兰登斯堡吗?
Were you at Landsberg?
你明知我有去
You know I was.
你以为他是和你我一样的士兵?
You think he's a soldier like you and me?
一个无辜的德国军官?
A fucking innocent German officer?
你过去三年到哪里去了?
Where the hell have you been for the past three years?
(德语)
Wer sind Sie?
Was machen Sie hier?
什么?
What?
(德语)
Ich habe gar nichts.
闭嘴
Shut up.
(德语)
Was machen Sie?
Ruhe.
(德语)
Sie sind der Kommandant.
Gehen Sie raus.
(德语)
Sie sind der Kommandant.
Welcher Kommandant?
(德语)
Vom Arbeitslager.
Ich weiss von keinem Arbeitslager.
(德语)
Sie haben die falsche Person.
不是
Nein, nein.
不要骗我
Don't fucking lie to me.
(德语)
Sie tauschen sich.
你看看你对我同胞做了什么!
See what you did to my fucking people?
(德语)
Nein.
他有罪
He's guilty.
- 李高特说他有罪... - 那就是有罪了
- Liebgott says so. - He probably is.
可恶的王八蛋 打他!
Goddamn son of a bitch. Shoot him.
开枪打他!
Shoot him!
不要
No.
军官不该逃的
Officers don't run.
战争结束了 换做是谁都会逃
The war's over, anybody would run.
在这山中仙境的夏日本该令人放松
Summer in this Alpine paradise should have been a welcome relief...
尤其是现在我们跟德国人和平相处之后
...especially now that we were at peace with the Germans.
每个人都只想回家
Everyone just wanted to go home.
法国 法国最棒了!
France. France was the best.
真的吗?
Really?
对! 五年了
Yeah, five years.
我想我每个国家都去过了 可是法国是最棒的
I think I was in every country, but France was the best.
意大利会是我第二个选择
Italy would be second for me.
俄罗斯不行 乌克兰还好
Russia is not desirable. Ukraine, it was okay.
你什么时候退伍?
So, when do you get out?
部队已经解散了 等连长转调后就可以离开了
The unit is discharged. We leave when my captain gets transferred.
这是我第二个战争的结束
It is the end of my second war.
老天
Jesus.
我要回家了 在曼海姆
I'm going home now to Mannheim.
这辆车由我来
I'll take this one.
(德语)
Passkarte, bitte.
好了
Okay.
嘿 韦伯斯特...
Hey, Webster.
- 我的替哨 - 不要向德军敬札
- My relief. - Don't salute the Germans.
别这样 我觉得蛮好玩的
Come on. I sort of get a kick out of it.
不管怎样 我现在有新的敌人 日本鬼子!
Anyway, I got me a new enemy. The Japs.
75点 你呢? 你是塔可亚出身的 对吗?
75 points. How about you? I mean, you're a Toccoa guy, right?
- 你有几点呢? - 你不会想要知道的
- How many you got? - Wouldn't you like to know?
退伍了是吗?
Discharged, huh?
- 去吧 你走 该我站了 - 好 我们回头见
- Go ahead, take off, it's my turn. - Okay, see you back at the farm.
81点
Eighty-one.
什么?
What?
我有81点
I have 81 points.
看来还是不够
Well, that's just not good enough.
我看能不能帮你找个便车
See about getting you a ride.
嘿!
Hey!
他们要去哪里?
Where are they going?
慕尼黑
Munich. Munchen, Munich.
你要去慕尼黑吗?
Wanna go to Munich?
(德语)
Mochten Sie nach Munchen gehen?
Ja, bitte.
上车
Get in.
真可惜
Too bad.
方向盘
Turn the wheel!
我的天
Oh, Jesus.
是二等兵杰诺维克
It's Private Janovec.
送他来时他已经断气了
He was dead when they brought him in.
75点
75 points.
- 什么? - 他只差10点
- What? - He was 10 points short.
敌军已经投降了 可是阿兵哥们还是继续死亡
The enemy had surrendered, but somehow men were still dying.
从诺曼底前服役至今的年轻士兵 虽然有着卓越的表现
Young men, who wanted to be home with their families by now...
就算想在此时与家人团聚
...who'd served with distinction since before Normandy...
却因点数不足而坐困在此
...were stuck here because they didn't have the points.
他们有的只是武器 酒精 还有手中太多的时间
What they did have plenty of were weapons, alcohol, and too much time on their hands.
他拼命想挣脱他的伞带
When all of a sudden, from out of nowhere...
突然不知从哪儿冒出来一个家伙 跳出树丛
...a guy jumps out of the hedgerow...
冲出来压住他的胸膛
...onto this guy's chest.
将刀子抵住他的喉咙大喊"你是哪一边的? "
Shoves a trench knife up against his throat and screams, "Whose side are you on?"
我听不懂
I don't get it.
在D日那天
It's D-day.
是第二排的比尔葛奈瑞 人称老淋病先生
It's 2nd platoon's own Bill Guarnere. Old' Gonorrhea himself.
才刚降落在诺曼底就兴奋的跟什么一样
Just landed in Normandy and wound up like I don't know what.
"你是哪一边的"? 真是个怪胎
"Whose side are you on?" What a fucking character!
他后来怎么样了?
What happened to him?
他的脚在巴斯通给炸断了
Got his leg blown off in Bastogne.
在这里等着
Wait here.
你还好吗 朋友? 你需要帮忙吗?
Are you okay, Mac, do you need some help?
他们一点汽油都不给我
They wouldn't give me any gas.
臭德仔
Krauts.
我试着解释
I tried to explain.
这些臭德军就是不听
This fucking limey wouldn't listen.
我想他是个少校
I think he was a Major.
你听着 阿兵哥 我们这里出问题了
Look, Private, we've got a problem here.
你有汽油吗?
Do you have any gas?
把你的枪给我好吗
Why don't you give me your weapon?
那我只好开他的吉普车 我想他是用不着了
Well, I guess I'll just use his Jeep. I don't think he's gonna be needing it.
你站在原地别走
Hold on a second there, all right?
老天
Jesus.
中士! 葛兰特中士
Sarge! Sergeant Grant!
中士
Sarge!
老天
Jesus.
怎样?
What?
他活不成了
He's not gonna make it.
你不能动手术吗?
You can't operate on him?
我没办法
Not me.
你需要一位脑外科医生
You'd need a brain surgeon.
就算你找到了 我也不认为有任何希望
And even if you had one, I don't think there's any hope.
你去把凶手抓来 我要活口 过来帮我
Find the shooter. Alive. Come on, help me.
你要干什么?
What are you doing?
我们去找脑外科医生
We're gonna go find a brain surgeon.
李 他要每个检查哨都要有位士官看管
Hey, Lieb. He wants a noncom guarding each roadblock...
每条离开镇上的道路 要有至少两位士兵看守
...and two men watching every road out of town.
大牛 马拉其 你们每人挑选一班...
Bull, Malark, you each pick a squad...
及一位目击者做逐屋搜索
...and one witness on a house to house search.
可以当场格杀这个混蛋吗?
Can we shoot this bastard on sight?
尽量留下活口
Try and take him alive.
葛兰特现在在哪里?
Where's Grant now?
他们送他去一间德军医院
They took him to a Kraut hospital...
看看能不能找到好医生
...to see if they could drum up any good doctors.
开门
Open up.
跟我来
Come with me.
为什么?
Why?
上吉普车
Get in the Jeep.
我们要去哪里?
Where're we going?
去医院 上车
To the hospital, get in.
你如果要对我开枪就动手
If you're going to shoot me, shoot me.
如果你不动手 就把枪拿开
If you're not, put the gun away.
快点 上吉普车
Get in the Jeep, now.
- 他怎么了? - 他头部中弹
- What happened to him? - He was shot in the head.
在半个小时前 快点!
Half hour ago. Come on.
如果你要他活下去 你就要帮我
If you want him to live, you'll help me.
首先把枪拿开
First by putting that away.
- 我们走 - 让我来开
- Let's go. - Let me drive.
我们可以快一点到
We'll get there faster.
老天 又是一手烂牌
Jesus. Again, what a hand.
不知道是谁比较惨 是我还是他?
I don't know who's taking a bigger beating, me or him.
玩别的游戏?
Wanna play a different game?
不用
No.
就玩这种 你只要把牌洗好 好吗?
Same game, just shuffle them up good, huh?
- 你还好吗? - 好 我很好
- You all right? - Yeah, I'm all right.
你要进去加入他们吗?
You wanna go in there and join in?
我应该进去叫他们别再打了
I should go in there and stop this.
佛洛依德 我们打牌就好 好吗?
Floyd, let's just play cards, all right?
人在哪里?
Where is he?
葛兰特还好吗?
How's Grant?
他还好吗?
Is he okay?
就是他吗?
This him?
就是他
That's him.
Ｉ连的新兵
Replacement I Company.
武器在哪里?
Where's the weapon?
什么武器?
What weapon?
当你跟军官说话时 你要说长官
When you talk to an officer, you say "sir."
叫宪兵来处理这个人渣
Have the MPs take care of this piece of shit.
- 葛兰特死了吗? - 没有
- Grant's dead? - No.
德国军医说他能活下来
Kraut surgeon says he's gonna make it.
硬汉 站起来 走了 快点 站起来
Hey, tough guy, on your feet. Come on, move, move it.
我猜那些是希特勒的相簿 长官
I'm guessing they were Hitler's photo albums, sir.
里面有很多他的照片
Sure had a lot of pictures of him in it.
你看到那些相簿却一本也没拿?
You looked at them, but you didn't take them?
是的 长官
That's right, sir.
我才不相信你
I don't believe you.
我会盯着你
I'll be watching you.
你可以走了
You're dismissed.
你最好别骗我
You'd better not be lying to me.
什么事?
What?
长官! 如果不会造成你太大困扰的话
Sir, if it's not gonna put you in too much of a bind...
我想请辞连队军士长的职位
...I'd like to resign as Company 1st Sergeant.
如果我能选择 我想念跟兄弟们一起的时光
If I had my choice I miss being back amongst the men.
我会很高兴担任幕僚士官 随便你要我去哪一排
I'd be happy to go to Staff Sergeant whichever platoon you wanna put me in.
我想你已经争取到自己降级的权利
Well, I guess you've earned your right to demote yourself.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
你要不要带葛兰特中士那一班?
You wanna take over Sergeant Grant's platoon?
那很好 长官
That would do fine, sir.
那就好 向皮卡克少尉报到
All right then, report to Lieutenant Peacock.
他要是找你麻烦就跟我说
Let me know if he gives you any trouble.
长官 你做决定了吗?
Oh, sir, you make your decision yet?
我决定了
Yeah, I did.
你心里还有什么打算?
So, what else is on your mind?
我知道Ｅ连在战后还需要一位连长
I know Easy Company's gonna need a Commanding Officer post-war.
一个能够支持他们避免他们自相残杀的人
Somebody to hold their hand keep them from killing each other.
最好是个了解兄弟的人
It better be somebody who knows what they're doing.
对 我完全同意
Yep, I couldn't agree more.
把他们交给不适任的人是绝对不负责任的
It's absolutely irresponsible to leave them in the hands of the wrong person.
他们是军方无比珍贵的资源
They're too much of a valuable resource to the military.
你决定留在陆军了?
So, you've decided to stay in the army?
是的 我要留下来陪他们
Yes, I'm gonna stay with the men.
我很高兴听到你这么说
Well, I'm glad to hear it.
所以有些人选择留下来
So, some of us would stay by choice...
可其他人却还困在这里 除非找到送走他们的理由
...but others were stuck if we couldn't find excuses to send them away.
这是个跳伞表演
So, it's an airborne exhibition.
他们会出动每一种盟军参战的飞机
They have one of every Allied combat plane they've used in the war.
我是说 是的 长官
I mean, yes, sir.
你是技术顾问 确定他们不会出错
You'll be like a technical adviser to make sure they get everything right.
我了解了 长官
I understand, sir.
很抱歉 不是你最想去的地方
I'm sorry it's not a more hospitable location.
不会的 长官 巴黎...还可以啦
No, sir. Paris is just fine.
如果你需要我去
You know, if you need me to go...
- 总有人要去的 - 是的 我们需要 我们绝对需要
- ...someone must be there. - Yeah, we do, we absolutely do.
司机会送你到你挑选的旅馆
And your driver will drop you off at a hotel of your choice.
我想我们短时间内 不会在这里再看到你
And I don't think we'll see you back here any time soon.
我不会让你失望的 长官
I won't let you down, sir.
卡伍德 对了...
Carwood, yes.
我想说的是...
I wanted to say...
或许你已经知道
...as you probably know...
陆军在颁给一个人战场委任书升他当军官后
...when they give a man a battlefield commission make him an officer...
通常不会让他待在同一连
...they usually don't let him stay with the same company.
是的 长官 我已经料想到这一天的到来
Yes, sir, I figured this was coming.
对 是怕兄弟们不会给他对军官应有的尊敬
Yeah, they're afraid the men won't show him the proper degree of respect as they would another officer.
这是个很好的理论 长官
It's a good theory, sir.
这是个白痴的理论 特别是用在你的身上
It's an idiotic theory especially in your case.
尽管如此 他们还是给了我重新指派你的选择
Nevertheless, they've given me the choice as to where to re-assign you...
而我想营指挥部应该是个好地方
...and I thought battalion headquarters might be a good place.
我想不出更好的地方了 长官
I can think of few better, sir.
很好
Good.
现在在机场那边有位德国将军
Right now, down at the airfield there is a German general who is a little POed...
对要向来自南费城的大兵贝比・赫夫朗投降有些迟疑
...about having to surrender to a private from South Philly.
- 他觉得有失他的身份 - 这我能了解 长官
- Thinks it's beneath his stature. - Understandable, sir.
对! 我想来自西维吉尼亚的卡伍德・李普顿少尉...
Yeah. I thought 2nd Lieutenant Carwood Lipton from West Virginia...
可以杀杀他的傲气
...could soothe his ruffled feathers.
没问题 长官
No problem, sir.
少校 这是不是从现在开始...我可以期待的工作形态?
Major, is this the type of job I can expect from now on?
对
Yeah. Yeah.
当我们不在湖边晒太阳的时候
When we're not sunning ourselves by the lake.
少尉
Lieutenant.
经由你的同意 我想跟兄弟们简短说些话
With your permission, I would like to address my men briefly.
没问题 将军
That'll be fine, General.
索柏上尉
Captain Sobel.
- 温特斯少校 - 索柏上尉
- Major Winters. - Captain Sobel.
敬礼是看官阶 不是看人的
We salute the rank, not the man.
(德语)
Manner...
...es war ein langer Krieg.
(德语)
Es war ein harter Krieg.
李高特?
Liebgott?
这是个漫长的战争 也是一场艰苦的战争
Men, it's been a long war, it's been a tough war.
(德语)
lhr habt tapfer und stolz fur euer Vaterland gekampft.
你们英勇...并骄傲的为祖国作战
You have fought bravely, proudly for your country.
(德语)
lhr seid eine besondere Gruppe...
你们是不平凡的一群
You are a special group...
(德语)
...die ineinander einen Zusammenhalt gefunden habt...
彼此紧密相连
...who have found in one another a bond...
(德语)
...wie er sich nur im Kampf entwickeln kann.
这样的友谊只存在战斗中
...that exists only in combat.
(德语)
Unter Kameraden...
在兄弟之间
Among brothers...
(德语)
...die Fuchshohlen geteilt haben.
共同使用散兵坑
...of shared foxholes.
(德语)
Die sich in schrecklichen Momenten...
...gegenseitig geschtutzt haben.
在最需要的时刻彼此扶持
Held each other in dire moments.
(德语)
Die den Tod zusammen gesehen haben.
Und gemeinsam gelitten haben.
你们看过死亡 一起接受磨难
Who've seen death and suffered together.
(德语)
Ich bin stolz...
...mit euch gedient zu haben.
我很骄傲能与你们每个人共同服役
I am proud to have served with each and every one of you.
(德语)
Sie alle verdienen ein langes und gluckliches...
...Leben in Frieden.
你们有权享受永远的快乐的和平生活
You deserve long and happy lives of peace.
毛巾
Towel, towel, towel, towel, towel.
谢谢!
Thanks.
看看这两个孩子
Take a look at these two kids.
他们究竟发生什么事了?
What the hell happened to them?
纽泽西 是不是?
New Jersey, huh?
对
Yeah.
考虑看看
Think about it.
有 我在考虑
Yeah, I am.
你睡醒了吗?
You awake yet?
睡醒?
Awake?
该上床睡觉了
Time to go to bed.
运气不好 吉米
Bad luck, Jimmy.
守得好
Nice play.
来吧 一人出局了
Come on, we got one down.
来吧 小不点 让我们解决韦伯斯特
Come on, Pee Wee, let's get Webster.
"巴克・康普顿"回到连上看大家 让大家知道他很好
Buck Compton came back to see the Company. To let us know that he was all right.
他后来成为洛杉矶的检察官
He became a prosecutor in Los Angeles.
他在罗伯特・肯里迪的谋杀案中 将凶手索罕定罪
He convicted Sirhan Sirhan in the murder of Robert Kennedy...
之后被指派任职于加州上诉法院
...and was later appointed to the California Court of Appeals.
"大卫・韦伯斯特"成为周六邮报、华尔街日报的专栏作家
David Webster became a writer for The Saturday Evening Post and Wall Street Journal...
之后他写了本有关鲨鱼的书
...and later wrote a book about sharks.
在1961年他独自出海之后
In 1961, he went out on the ocean alone...
就没有人再见过他了
...and was never seen again.
跑
Go, go, go!
"强尼・马丁"回到原先他在铁路公司的工作
Johnny Martin would return to his job at the railroad...
然后开设他自己的建筑公司
...and then start his own construction company.
在亚历桑纳及蒙大拿两地来回奔波
He splits his time between Arizona and a place in Montana.
"乔治・鲁兹"在罗德岛州的普拉福登斯担任杂务工
George Luz became a handyman in Providence, Rhode Island...
由于他极佳的人缘
...and as a testament to his character...
1600人在1998年参加了他的丧札
...1600 people attended his funeral 1998.
"罗医官"于1998年在路易斯安那逝世
Doc Roe died in Louisiana in 1998.
他成为一位建筑承包商
He'd been a construction contractor.
"法兰克・派康提"回到芝加哥 在一间邮局担任邮递员
Frank Perconte returned to Chicago and worked a postal route as a mailman.
"乔・李高特"回到旧金山
Joe Liebgott returned to San Francisco...
开他的出租车
...and drove his cab.
"大牛・蓝道曼"是我带过最好的士兵之一
Bull Randleman was one of the best soldiers I ever had.
他在阿肯色州从事挖掘土方的事业
He went into the earth-moving business in Arkansas.
他还在那里
He's still there.
"奥顿・摩尔"带了一件特殊的纪念品回到怀俄明
Alton More returned to Wyoming with a unique souvenir...
就是希特勒的私人相簿
...Hitler's personal photo albums.
他在1958年因车祸过世
He was killed in a car accident in 1958.
"佛洛依德・泰伯特"在解甲归田后 便与我们失去联络
Floyd Talbert, we all lost touch with in civilian life...
直到1981年 在他去世前的聚会中才再见到他
...until he showed up at a reunion just before his death in 1981.
我们战后的生活人人不同
How we lived our lives after the war was as varied as each man.
"卡伍德・李普顿"成为玻璃工厂主管
Carwood Lipton became a glass-making executive...
掌管的工厂遍及全球
...in charge of factories all over the world.
在北卡罗荣纳过着美好的生活
He has a nice life in North Carolina.
"哈利・威尔旭" 他娶了"凯蒂・葛罗根"
Harry Welsh, he married Kitty Grogan...
成为威克司巴尔宾州分校的行政主管
...became an administrator for the Wilkes-Barre Pennsylvania school system.
"隆纳德・史毕尔"留在陆军 参加了朝鲜战争
Ronald Speirs stayed in the army served in Korea...
并在1958年返回德国担任斯班朵监狱的典狱长
...and in 1958, returned to Germany as governor of Spandau prison.
以中校阶级退伍
He retired a Lieutenant Colonel.
叫他们集合
Get them round.
Ｅ连 成谈话队形!
Easy Company, school circle!
对Ｅ连来说 这是D日后的第434天
For Easy Company, it was D-day plus 434.
脑筋快的人该想到了 派康提
A fast man would've had it, Perco.
注意听 有消息宣布
Listen up, got some news.
今天早上 杜鲁门总统接受了日本的无条件投降
This morning President Truman received the unconditional surrender from the Japanese.
战争结束了
War's over.
不管点数 勋章或是伤痕
Regardless of points, medals, or wounds...
每个101空降师兄弟都要回家了
...each man in the 101st Airborne would be going home.
我们每个人都会因为共同经历而永远相系
Each of us would be forever connected by our shared experience.
每个人也必须尽力重新加入世界
And each would have to rejoin the world as best he could.
战争结束了!
War is over
"路易士・尼克森"在战后不是很得意
Lewis Nixon had some tough times after the war.
离了几次婚
He was divorced a couple of times.
1956年娶了"葛瑞丝" 从此一帆风顺
Then in 1956, he married a woman named Grace and everything came together for him.
他与她共度余生 四处旅游
He spent the rest of his life with her, traveling the world.
我的好友路易于1995年过世
My friend, Lew, died in 1995.
我接受了他的工作 在尼克森化肥产品担任人事经理
I took up his job offer and was a personnel manager at the Nixon nitration works until I was called back...
直到1950年我被征召回部队 去训练军官及突击队员
...into service in 1950 to train officers and rangers...
可我没有选择去朝鲜并以此为业 我已经历太多战争
...but I chose not to go to Korea. I'd had enough of war.
我在宾州贺胥待了下来 最后终于找到一处农场
I stayed around Hershey, Pennsylvania finally finding a little farm.
世界上平静的一个小角落
A little peaceful corner of the world...
到现在我仍旧住在这里
...where I still live today.
我没有一天不想 那些曾经与我一起服役...
And there is not a day that goes by that I do not think of the men I served with...
却未能有机会享受没有战争的日子的兄弟们
...who never got to enjoy the world without war.
这是一个很奇特的感觉 (迪克・温特斯)
It's a very unusual feeling.
这是件很不平凡的事 它是个非比寻常的连结
It's a very unusual happening and it's a very unusual bonding.
我们知道我们可以彼此依赖 (卡伍德・李普顿)
We knew that we could depend on each other...
所以我们是很紧密的团体
...and so, we were a close-knit group.
就是勇气 难以置信的勇敢 (马拉其 唐诺)
Just brave, so brave it was unbelievable.
我最崇拜比尔葛奈瑞还有乔托伊
And I don't know anybody that I admire more than Bill Guarnere and Joe Toye.
他们都很特别
And they were very, very special.
我只是在大战里的一部分 如此而已
I'm just one part of the big war, that's all.
一小部分 (比尔・加尼尔 中士)
One little part.
而我很骄傲能参与其中
And I'm proud to be a part of it.
有时候它会使我哭泣
Sometimes it makes me cry.
真正的男子汉 英雄们 (大兵 赫弗朗)
The real men the real heroes are the fellows...
是那些还埋在那里与殉国返乡被葬的人
...that are still buried over there and those that came home to be buried.
感觉好象是你以为你能做任何事
It seemed like you thought that you could do...
当战争结束后你回到社会 (西福地・鲍尔斯)
...just about anything and after the war was over and you came back out.
你丧失许多这种能力
Well, you lost a lot of that...
至少我是如此
...or at least I did.
我丧失了原有的信心
I lost all that confidence.
我只是想活下来 如此而已 (约翰・马丁)
We was hoping to stay alive, that's all, you know.
亨利五世跟他的士兵们说话
Henry the Fifth was talking to his men.
他说从今天到世界末日
He said, "From this day to the ending of the world...
我们永远会被记得
"...we in it shall be remembered.
我们幸运的少数 我们相系相依的兄弟
"We lucky few, we band of brothers.
谁今日与我共同浴血 他就是我的兄弟
"For he who today sheds his blood with me shall be my brother."
你还记得
Do you remember...
我祖母写给我的信吗?
...the letter that my granny wrote me?
你记得吗? 记得最后怎么结束的?
You do? Do you remember how I ended it?
我很珍惜这段记忆
"I cherish the memories of a question...
有天我孙子问我一个问题
"my grandson asked me the other day...
他问我:
"...when he said:
"爷爷 你是大战中的英雄吗? "
"Grandpa, were you a hero in the war?"
我回答: 不是
Grandpa said, "No...
可是我与英雄们一起服役
"...but I served in the company of heroes."